hey welcome everyone for another wasabi
research club conversation this time we
are going to go through a paper from
Paul Severson called why I'm not an
entropy the outer is the inventor of the
onion routing protocol is not working on
tour right now
and since Aviv is not here there is no
presentation on this paper right now so
I'm just going to read the abstract one
line from the conclusion and let's see
where we go from there so what does it
mean to be anonymous in network
communications or centroids thesis is
that both the theoretical literature and
the deployed systems have gotten the
ants were essentially wrong the ants
were have been wrong because they apply
the wrong metric to the wrong adversary
model I indicate problems in the
established adversary models and matrix
for anonymity as well as implications
for the design and analysis of anonymous
communication systems so this is the
abstract it might be to obstruct but
hurt but there was a nice quote from the
paper that that actually explains what
it really wants wants to prove that the
central the central point is that the
model on which all existing work on
anonymity the entropies model is broken
for open or widely shared communications
so he doesn't like the the entropies
model that's that's the point there and
why we see some unfortunately the the
outward I couldn't reach him maybe I
sent the message to the wrong email
address so he is not with us however we
have with us Harry from Network who has
some interesting context on the on how
this paper came around and
but the halter might be thinking might
was thinking when when he he did this
paper so Harry I give the words to you
so could you start over but you but you
started saying just before the show yeah
so I'll just give a little bit of an
introduction to this paper you know
soso to to sort of notes first of all
[Music]
this paper comes from a long-standing
argument around how to build anonymous
communication and I think in order to
understand why this is billion ominous
communication systems are difficult it's
useful to compare them classical
cryptography so you know for years
people build crypto systems and maybe
they work maybe they get in and
eventually they they sort of boiled it
down to the dogs whole security you had
a well-defined adversary I'm sorry we
are losing you your voice is just
getting lower and lower over no it's not
is anyone hearing it I'll just try gets
close to the microphone yeah no it's
good yeah okay so I'll just what I was
trying to say is that essentially
anonymous communication systems people
were building them but they didn't
really have any principles to understand
why one design would be better than
another design so in particular you know
why would for example tour which is
called an onion routing system
be better or worse than a mixed Network
and a lot of this comes from essentially
a misunderstanding that happened very
early round probably 2003 or four when
tor came out so pulse iverson weirdly
enough was a philosopher and like many
philosophers he he couldn't find a job
and essentially the US Navy didn't have
huge budgets so they hired philosophers
because they knew about logic and they
thought they could train them into
computer scientists cheaper than
actually hiring computer scientists and
one day one of Paul's friends had this
he said well Paul would be possible
every time I connect to the internet I
leak my IP address and would it be
possible to build a system where this
doesn't happen and Paul had never
thought about this question before his
background was actually in something
called epistemic logic but he kind of
had this concept which became Onion
Routing
and the concept is basically the only
way you can get anonymity is by passing
a message through essentially a network
of strangers and you know at each point
does it lay encryption you unwrap it and
that that was really genuinely kind of
Paul's insight now the problem is Paul
was not aware that David charm and other
people have been working on mixed
networks since the 80s and mixed
networks basically he said if you have a
sender and receiver you hand packets to
a mixer and they basically shuffle these
packets like a deck of cards they mix
them and then they launch them all out
at the same time and because they've all
been sort of launched at the same time
and their order has been essentially
randomly permute 'add you can't tell if
the packets are encrypted as long as
different
senders are sending packets to the mixer
and different receivers are getting it
that the packets who the senders and
receivers are and that's the goal of
sender and receiver unlinked ability and
mixed networks were built so that even
an adversary which is observing the
entire network you know for example the
NSA couldn't tell which sender was
sending which message the what receiver
with any real advantage now what Paul
now people kind of you know mix Network
said they did this but there is no
really way to quantify there's a bunch
of different mixed Network designs which
design is is better than another for
example should you have one mixer so you
have a chain of mixers should you have a
peer-to-peer network of mixes there is
all these different designs being thrown
around and eventually George donita's
who was NIMS co-founder but
unfortunately now at Libre and Claudia
Diaz
kayuu loving but also now at NIMH
basically simultaneously thought up in
2004 they said well the way to measure
in an enemy is not just an enemy set but
entropy entropy is a well-defined
mathematical notion we can say that you
know given one message we can quantify
what the possible sinners receivers are
using entropy metrics and we can also
kind of chain those metrics so that we
can say well the message us this much
entropy in this hop this much entropy
after being mixed for so long if this
much intra peed another hop and that
Paul had no concept that that work was
even going on so he independently
thought of Onion Routing at or and then
when he submitted the Tor paper to this
conference call the privacy enhancing
technologies a workshop they pezzi said
oh this is a weird mix
you've invented and I'm all basically
like well that's not the point I'm not
trying to mix traffic tor doesn't mix
traffic we're not concerned about an
adversary that watches the entire
network we're concerned about hiding IP
addresses and and you know trying to
open circuits basically to allow and he
thought this was a much more real-world
design and now actually thinks that the
the Snowden's latest book permanent
record we actually know that before tour
but actually what happen is when the CIA
wanted to for example do a google search
on someone they basically had to open a
whole operation
you know basically buy a computer and go
to some weird place make a fake company
just to basically do Google searches
without revealing an IP address that
went back to you know CIA gov that's in
you know Snowden said well tor is great
because it does defended the IP address
so the CIA did have to do spend all this
money anymore and tor is a great system
it's it's the and when Paul Fogg tour
and Roger and Nick actually built it it
was the only real working anonymity
system mixed networks were only used for
what was called cyberpunk email
remailers so they send anonymous emails
to people and people to be honest
Mixmaster which nicks from tor worked on
and roger who eventually worked on tor
worked on with george these systems like
Mixmaster from lance s men and makes
minion from george roger and nick they
never really took off they were used by
cypher punks but they were kind of used
unusable and analyst problems you send
the message you never know if you got a
response it was really tricky Justi just
to make sense of them for ordinary users
while you know paul argue that tour was
really easy to did one thing and did it
very well in the he felt it did it you
know what the people the crazy people
were interested in mixed nets we're
doing was a bit wacky because in reality
you know you don't have an anonymous set
that most adversaries know about the
internet is not a you know uniformly
connected
you can't send messages out all at the
same time the network has all these
structured links kind of built into ISPs
by default and he actually argues I
think he argues in this paper pretty
successfully that even though tor
doesn't really fit this entropy based
way to define an M&E anonymous
communication systems it's a it's a it's
it's it's it's fighting it's fighting a
realistic adversary so he's really
arguing that entropy and anonymity sets
are not the best way to measure the
success and the performance and that
just the capability of a real world
anonymous communication system my
opinion on this is at the time that Paul
wrote this he was basically right but
that now weirdly enough you know 10 20
years down the road it's actually the
threat that Paul feels unrealistic an
adversary that can watch the entire
network and record all the communication
between every link is actually realistic
so that's kind of my disagreement with
Paul but I think that's some context
with the papers Paul's trying to defend
tor against people who says all this
system it doesn't really produce great
entropy it's not as good as I mixed that
it you know it doesn't really have a
good definition for why it's anonymous
or why it's more secure does that make
sense that explanation totally okay so I
mean I don't know I mean I'd like to
hear what people think about tor and
entropy and defining anonymous
communication
I'm just thinking that I always knew
there's something wrong with tor and
that kind of like explained it in some
sense within some sense some sense I
mean I wouldn't say that there's
anything wrong with tor it's just that
what Paul's arguing is that tor has a
particular threat model which is you
know it's trying to hide the IP address
in the origin of large amounts of
traffic
and that doesn't rip that threat model
which is realistic doesn't have anything
really to do with entropy I mean I would
argue Paul was right at the time and now
time to change the bit but I still think
Paul is a point that anonymous systems
aren't easily mathematically definable
and so in classical cryptography you
know you have these very nice precise
formal definitions of security like you
have ciphertext and plaintext and given
some ciphertext can I get to the plain
text can I fake a signature can I I mean
these are very well defined notions and
you don't really and this is I think the
philosophical point of paper you don't
really have these definitions and at
least in a really well understood form
in anonymous communications and maybe a
simple something simple which seems
correct like entropy might not actually
be the best way to define how an
anonymous communication system should be
judged so sorry guys I had to leave for
five minutes
but I can I can actually say something
what what you just said I'd say I I
don't
at least from my impression or
impression I'm pretty sure that this is
not really about the title is a bit
click Beatty but this is not really
about why his is not an entropy
what what is arguing is that entropy is
not sufficient in quantifying anonymity
because because of Tor because you
cannot quantify because you cannot
cannot put the entropy swaddle into
torso you need some some some more more
things that how you would
quantify the unanimity and compare it
between different anonymity networks and
he had he had a solution proposal but he
desirably go into it and I didn't really
understand it because this is a how he
puts it it's a breaking paper it's not a
solution it just this wide
anthropometric would not be sufficient
in in in comparing anonymity systems
would that be the same impressions or or
or or did you guys think that this this
is really just just saying that no the
anthropometric is completely wrong we
shouldn't use it yeah I mean that that
leads into the next question right
if entropy might be a good model for
communication like an anonymizing
communications even if we think that it
is that is it still applicable to
anonymizing Bitcoin transaction and to
analyzing coin Jones I'm not sure yeah
actually that's that's a good point that
as I see it in in Cohen joins the the
things what he's arguing is just not
there because in Cohen joins really what
really matters is the entropy because
every information is somewhat there on
the blockchain already so you can you
can cannot really go wrong with the
entropy on the other that that would be
that that would have be my point there
too
anyway yeah Adam I actually agree both
with you and Max here because so far
everything that you're doing for
enjoying in a program way it's still
relying on the entropy one way or
another
therefore yes everything that we have
heard so far about war and its flaws you
know all that in and about the paper
being against entropy means entropy
being valid probably I would say were
available enough reasoning coinsurance
there are thousands of methods to
achieve thousands of goals
therefore I think we just need to
understand whether the method should be
applicable or probably a bit modified or
actually useless or coin joint ease
which we are referring to right here
during this calls and I think that it
might be twit like you can be tweaked
but I do not think that we should just
cross the entropy out of everything that
we are doing to ensure they are green I
mean we have an entropy model exactly
one for Cohen joins the portsmen entropy
which is maybe the Shannon entropy if
you don't know what other why I think
that's that's that's really not a good
good way to go about that because you
can get surprises if you are not
weighing in the link link breaking stuff
like or the knapsack paper actually
worked out to degree so so yeah the
entropy model we should not repeat
that's for sure but in order to use it
we would have to work it out properly
right
yeah I actually a question here where is
the difference between Ronnie entropy
and Shannon entropy and Boltzmann and
repeat we just talked about it last
epistle then we get to the conclusion
that we don't know or what we think we
know is not what the author thinks he
knows so so I don't know so the thing is
that in the Boltzmann paper wait I want
to do it quickly because this is not
about the Boltzmann paper so it's not
even a paper it's a gist in the boys
longest the entropy looks like Shawn on
entropy so I started calling it Shannon
entropy under the comments and the
author said that oh it's it's not
Shannon entropy and well okay the paper
called what's Mars so it must be the
boys on entropy right but then oh we've
said there is no Boltzmann constant here
so it's not the boys when entropy and it
looks like the Shannon entropy so it
must be the Shannon entropy so it
supposed to be the Shannon entropy but
the author might know better and we
don't have time to really investigate
that and not even that important
question so so and I'm sorry for
interrupting do I understand correctly
that basically now there is no clear
differentiation between those three
types of entropy I could answer this
really briefly which is the way to think
about is that Shannon is entropy in bits
and so you know bits have you know
essentially it's two dimensions
everything's log base two
Rini entropy basically says well let's
imagine we have entropy across multiple
dimensions you know up to infinite
numbers of dimensions and tries to
capture that all within one measurement
so you can have entropy with three
dimensions or four dimensions or five
dimensions at least that's how I
understand it but I mean for most
computer science uses of the term
entropy I think we're talking Shannon
entropy the other entropy versions are
to mine understanding which is I think
quite limited in this regard er are
mostly useful and say like physics for
example so I wouldn't get too hung up on
it I think basically people mean
including I don't know why Paul Magers
ran the entropy in the beginning here
but I think most people basically when
they say entropy they mean Shannon
entropy they don't really mean anything
else hmm
and we are talking about another paper
that was the last last episode last
session that the entropy was defined as
follows so the entropy so the the gist
is called the Boyett's one distinct
advancement so that would say that it is
the Boltzmann entropy but the entropy is
defined as followed look to and the
number of possible valid combinations
which looks like the Shannon entropy
right it does unless there is some
circumstances for example that this like
semi law operates or there is some
additional condition or something like
that I mean a lot of things in
mathematics there are very similar to
each other unless there is AK one
condition that changes the whole thing
and actually defines some some property
something like that anyway yes this
paper talked a bit about entropy to that
I don't even know what he I mean maybe
all all he said is just his entropy in a
way that's different kind of entropy is
that he is preferring the Iranian
through P right am I am I remembering
right here
okay I remember well yes so he prefers
the rainy Anthropy for for some reasons
oh all right I think maybe I mean it
might be useful to talk about some of
what Paul argues so so so so what what
Paul's argument turns to entropy he says
well you know you have this kind of
theoretical way of measuring if
someone's anonymous or not but how
useful is that in the real world so
Paul's like argument is he says well you
know he says that he actually calls it
of everyone correctly that the threat
model of the man right we says well you
know the man can basically do anything
your network watch all all the nodes
delay packets drop packets compromise
compromise your the nodes in your
anonymous communication network and he
says you know when you look at like what
mixed nets were designed to fight they
were designed to fight an adversary that
Paul at least at the time he wrote this
feels isn't very realistic which is a
global passive adversary so this is an
adversary that can watch all of the
communication in a network all the
inputs and the outputs and every single
hop between every router in the Internet
and he says well you know imagine you
have this perfect mix net what you know
I think actually calls out Mix Master by
name which is the anonymous email
remailer that's you know kind of came
from the cypherpunks and he says you
know it's it's great if you have a
hundred people using this and those
people you know the entropy you can't
distinguish them at all so you know your
entropy is like whatever you know to the
eight whatever you know like eight or
eight or not you know something quite
point eight or nine bits of entropy
right so you can you said well that's
great you know you have a fair amount of
entropy but push comes to shove
you still have a very small amount of
users and then he says look at tour
which tour doesn't even claim and
explicitly doesn't claim to defend
against adversaries that can watch the
whole network but the impulses was not
very realistic that watching the whole
network instead what they would do is
they would attack particular routers
they would watch particular routers they
would you know do denial of service
attacks and all sorts of other stuff and
that this kind of adversary which I
think he kind of at the end
talks about being close to what's called
the roving adversary Asst or local
adversary that's very powerful miss prey
can do kind of what's called active
attacks can actually modify and change
packets rather than just writing them
down this kind of adversaries more
realistic it's it's less resource it's a
Paul argues it's a huge amount of
resources to copy every packet send on
the Internet
but it's not that many resources to copy
all the packets sit through an
individually suspicious router or every
packet going to like an individually
suspicious hidden service or tor exit
node you know whatever going to The
Pirate Bay
and and I think that's actually a really
strong argument it's it's not
necessarily false I think it's actually
correct and then what he argues is that
you know mixed networks that if no one's
using them that is it really that
anonymous while if you look at tor tor
just has a kind of poor entropy isn't
very good against global passive
adversaries but has a lot of users it's
very diverse and because tor circuits
keep switching every you know whatever
ten minutes or so so your entry node and
your exit node in the path through the
network changes every ten minutes or
whatever the the rate is that it's very
hard for an adversary to realistically
intercept too much of your traffic and
and so polls are that's a
more this kind of local active attacks
are much more realistic than these kind
of global passive attacks I think that's
a an interesting question which model is
more realistic and for what
quote-unquote the man can actually do so
I'd like to know what people think about
that I mean you can't but yeah but yours
so you can't can you how can you even
put the the Onion Routing into into an
entropy conception there is there is you
can't can do anything you can't define
entropy dare you you can't do anything
do you agree with that
so far or you think there is an anthro
pissed model that properly covers the
Onion Routing
use case and I I think it's it's wrong
to throw entropy out the window because
you can say well you know the the set of
all users of tor assume that you know
these packets or these circuits are
switched often enough you know or at
least unlink able in some regard to at
least their IP address but it is tricky
to think about that too really because
it's not actually true to basically say
tor has an easily measured an on be set
instead it's it's better to say you know
tor basically relies on a large
peer-to-peer network and a diversity of
routers to build some sort of practical
notion of anonymity and I think that
that's not incorrect that being said I I
I feel like Paul kind of what I would
say throws the baby out with the
bathwater so I think you know it's not
correct to say that mixed networks can
only defend against global passive
adversaries there's lots of I mean at
the time and Paul wrote that that was
basically true
but nowadays like Lou picks and NIM we
built active adversary attacks in and a
lot of them issues which Paul highlights
that networks are issues of usability
and performance and while I think it's
very very hard for mix networks to
achieve the performance of Tor I do
think they're getting a lot better
usability made a lot better and the
entropy is still a valid metric it
shouldn't be the only metric but it's if
you can't really give
indistinguishability between a global
passive adversary then it's not clear if
your system is is actually anonymous and
a strong sense because where I kind of
disagree with Paul's I think the NSA is
effectively a global passive adversary
that it is I mean you know maybe Iran
can't pull it off maybe you know France
can't pull it off but I think the
Americans combined at least GCHQ can
because they control a lot of their
insight the lots of routers actually do
mass traffic analysis on a level which I
think Paul thought was unrealistic yeah
but but the competing Sibylla ideas came
came in here that the NSA can't can't
watch China's traffic and China can't
watch America's traffic and and so on
right the big cities are competing with
each other because they don't share the
information with each other even even
the man even there is no word government
that is is there something missing from
that logic that that they can still
watch somehow each other's territory or
traffic yeah I think that's that's a
good point but it's it what Paul is
assuming or tor assumes is that your
threat model is this kind of locally
bound that
for sehri so that you know your threat
models the Chinese government and your
for example an American and you want or
Chinese dissident and you're trying to
basically escape that adversary should
only monitor a small portion of the
network may be only the Tor entry points
inside China but once you're you know
out of those of that network they can't
it's unrealistic for China that to
monitor the tor exit knows what you're
mostly going to let's say Silicon Valley
services Facebook Google whatever
Wikipedia that being said I don't know I
don't think that means you need to throw
in two P out because it's still useful
measure and it's also true that even
though maybe it's true that there's no
world government that can monitor all
the traffic all the time you know if I'm
the US government I can still monitor a
lot of entry nodes most of the entry
nodes which are in Europe and in the
United States and I can definitely
monitor the exit notes which in the
United States and therefore these kind
of timing correlation attacks that Paul
basically says well they're just kind of
theoretically interesting but they're
not practical I think those aren't
practical and I think the reason is
there's even been empirical stays it's
war I think Stephen Murdoch was the
first person to point this out the busy
says you know because most tor nodes are
in Europe and most users are toward the
United States and most big Internet
services in the United States you
actually look at tor traffic the
majority of it is folks coming from the
United States having the traffic shipped
over to Europe going through a few
relays in Europe and through the Chaos
Computer Club or whatnot and then being
shipped back to America to access Google
or Wikipedia or you know Amazon or
whatever and that's I think it while
it's unrealistic that an adversary can
monitor maybe every single internet
packet because you know China the US may
not cooperate or rush in the u.s. may
not cooperate it's probably true that
the but given a sir
user they might be able to monitor a
large portion and that portion is large
enough to reasonably approximate a
global passive adversary and so that's I
think the lesson from that would be sort
of something saying like oh you know
tour is great if your enemy is the
Chinese government it doesn't really
work super well China right now but it's
great if your enemies like a Chinese
government or the Iranian government or
even the French government or you know
the Hungarian government or you know a
government that doesn't have huge
amounts of surveillance powers but if
your enemies the United States
government and you happen to be in
Europe or the US or somewhere that's you
know not directly the adversarial with
them you know these attacks can story
thinker or not unrealistic does that
make sense yes can I since since you're
here and you know we have some
theoretical knowledge on mix networks
and and such because we reviewed some
papers regarding LDC nets dining
cryptographer networks but but you have
more practical knowledge on that and
it's it's not completely about this
paper but but since you're here I would
like to ask you that you know let's
let's make it let's let's make a
difference there that there is tor
traffic when you are accessing exit
nodes and the restore traffic when you
are inside the onion Network and you are
accessing only onion nodes on your sites
how would you how would you say but
what's the difference there is that
ultimately safer or or there are just
just this huge horse according to you in
in the privacy of those when you are
accessing onion only yeah I mean I mean
one huge advantage that tor has over
mixed networks is this ability to
essentially do web browser
and a half exit notes there's a really
clear mixed networks are not by nature
generically able to access any internet
service because the Internet by tcp/ip
by nature is kind of works in this or
stream based format and mixed nuts mix
every packet individually and so that
doesn't work very well for stream based
networks on some level I just want I
just want say I mean tour I think may
even be some sort of local optima might
be the best you could do for web
browsing and I think it's it you need
I'm not convinced that a lot of these
decentralized VPN concepts these other
things I'm seeing thrown around are ever
gonna be better than tour but I to P or
I don't know I so it's orchid thing I'm
not convinced 100% that will they're
better than tour I think it's
interesting they exist but and maybe
they have some incentive-based
advantages but they're not necessarily
going to be better that being said tour
onion services are definitely would
definitely be more secure because you're
always inside the Tor network so you
don't have these exit nodes that the NSA
or the man or you know the Chinese
government whoever could monitor very
easily I think you know you do have
hidden services you know inside it Tor
network and there can be a tax on they
can be attempts to D in autumn eyes with
hidden services there's been a lot of
research on that last few years and I I
would actually like to know from you
guys if people still feel hidden
services are safe I still basically
think they're safe and they work really
well or much safer than using a web
browser to a non hidden service and in
it's an advantage of Tor that they work
in and mixed networks essentially every
service inside of the mixed network has
to be kind of a little bit like a hidden
service because mixed network services
don't easily interface with websites
like the internet generic internet
services like tor can provide so yeah I
mean I know there a lot of attacks on
things like dark markets and stuff over
the last year or two that seemingly have
gotten worse i I don't anyone tracking
those I mean does there seem to be any
systemic issues with Toyota services I
would definitely say they're safer than
not using them but I'm not sure how
they're holding out right now like in
the real world I don't really hear news
about people getting the anonymized
because of Tor and it might not be
because tor is so secure but because
there are just so many low-hanging
fruits that that they can can go after
like oh the statistics is 60% of all a
dark net market users send the money
from dark net markets to know your
customer exchanges directly so I mean
why would you try to deny the Tor
network you have you have such
low-hanging fruits there too yeah
another another point you brought up DC
nuts is I mean let's just be very
there's basically like three fundamental
categories of anonymous communication
systems on the network level there is
Onion Routing systems like tor which are
effectively are kinds of what operate
effectively is a kind of decentralized
VPN let's say for a stream based circuit
based message internet traffic there's
mixed nets which basically mix messages
and a lot of the critique of Paul
against mixed nuts is he says well look
you know that that's there's those
threat models are very unrealistic and
no one really uses in the real world
while tour provides is very practical
benefit in terms of anonymity against
what he considers to be realistic
adversaries he's definitely right but DC
nuts are interesting so DC nuts without
any argument provide
with better or not enmity then mix
networks I mean they do there's this
kind of no question there because
everyone kind of does the computation on
the same packets but then I think a lot
of the critiques that Paul has against
mixed networks I would say mixed network
technology has evolved enough that those
critiques may not be necessary anymore
we'll talk about that maybe next time
but that those critiques are still very
possible against these see nets because
these see Nets you know have this
problem where everyone has to send the
messages at the same time and to all the
other participants and in real world
networks that that's really hard so I'd
like to know what people think about DC
Nets here okay I think deke read was
working on one I know Sarah from the
open privacy foundation is working on
water people interested in DC Nets are
trying to use them the thing is at least
my conclusion when we reviewed we review
the DC Nets paper and we reviewed queens
of plus plus which provides a DC net for
Bitcoin mixing and what he said there is
that when message sizes must be uniform
that's this kind of that's obvious but
the other thing is they argued that and
I'm not sure I understood the why but
they argued that that messages must be
fresh messages must be always fresh and
you cannot do a DC net that works
properly if the messages are not fresh
and with coin shaffer they actually
start that Vedic oh no no that was
decent not the Kratt sorry then I don't
know about the cred but via the argument
was there if the messages are not fresh
then you cannot do the DC Nets which
kind of means that it's it's useless for
communications
but for for their bit
purposes was was was good that any
anyone has remembers differently alright
so yeah I mean one way to think about DC
nuts is that you know it's like like you
said this is a very good example on
paper they have they're resistant to
more attacks and are more anonymous than
mixed nuts and torn
no questions asked but I think you know
when the points Paul's making is he
doesn't really talk about DC Nets and
while I'm not enter pissed is that even
though you had a DC net that had this I
kind of theoretically wonderful entropy
and worked against these theoretically
very powerful threat models the fact of
the matter is because it has these kind
of assumptions on fresh messages and
synchronous message passing and stuff
it's a really good system on paper but
it's unclear if any system that you'd
actually build would actually be
anonymous in any real sense that was
based on DC - well tor is the reverse
tor on paper you know I may not have
very formal definitions may not seem to
be that anonymous but has been this huge
real-world success story so even though
I'm working on it mixed net when the
folks from like member Wimble some of
them approached me they said what you
know member one ball has is like
interactive step in it which is
obviously something that needs network
level privacy and when they approached
me they said well should we use a mixed
net or tor I said I think you know mix
them the future is fine but for what
you're doing right now Jesus you've
already deployed nimble Wimble this is a
very dangerous attack on your
transaction privacy so in the name of
God use anonymous communication networks
that the largest possible anonymity set
and that therefore the largest possible
every user so you should use tor right
now rather than wait around for the NIM
mix net or try to build your own DC net
or something like that and I think
that's you know to be honest still the
case law systems I still think it's for
a lot of systems I mean
or works has tons of users now and that
shouldn't be thought about so from it
from a Bitcoin perspective I guess what
is likes I've read lots of papers about
anonymous Bitcoin transactions and new
kinds of privacy hands cryptocurrency
but I I think in reality like what you
said most people use Bitcoin and they
use mixers what are most people actually
using like in the real world that
provides good enough anonymity basically
that's pretty much it some people use
money rule most people use exchanges oh
yeah because he knows and and the
exchanges they use exchanges as mixers
so it's okay so it's like you explain
how would you use the exchange the mixer
just by translating the coin around a
bunch and oh no you send it to an
exchange and then you'll be draw it and
that's my chicken yeah yeah just Israel
to a new address that's it yes so it
doesn't provide you any anonymity
against the actual service provider just
for the outsiders right okay so some of
us store like they're just minting new
addresses basically and the exchange is
meeting that transaction exactly heats
it's not not rocket science but manually
created with an exchange yeah and how's
the real world attacks on this stuff
going so I had a Anya who was working on
the looping and mimics that she she
actually weirdly enough used to work for
chained alysus and my understanding is
that it's still very difficult for Chan
alysus to break most mixers and monera
I don't know what the extent I mean III
still feel it seems like even these very
simple techniques I wouldn't really use
them or advise when to use them but they
might I mean I don't
are you seeing any evidence these
techniques are being broken that
exchanges are watching out for this
behavior pattern and or what's going on
I mean what's the real world analysis no
I I don't think it can be broken
I mean 'men about wasabi but
specifically it cannot be broken because
the ones are equal so so that's it but
then people start merging their coins
together so that when when some people
do some really stupid things like they
come with no 10,000 Bitcoin and mixing
with 520 different kinds for two days
and then mix all their coins together
that's when they get obviously the
anonymize because well you can't hide an
elephant between a bunch of chiidren now
it's a good question if if some people
who who merge a bunch of coins together
like tens or hundreds of coins if they
get D anonymized in the same way too
like the very big guy and I'm not quite
sure I tried a couple of times but it's
it's computationally infeasible to to
try to find the valid valid matchings so
I'm not I think it is definitely not
getting the anonymized in practice and
even with people who are using it very
incorrectly they don't get D anonymized
because it's computationally expensive
and they are not trying to find
solutions they are not trying to do
anonymize at all because of the same
thing that i just said that most people
are sending money from darkened markets
to exchanges and and there is just so
many low-hanging fruits that they they
aren't even trying it seems so what they
settled weed is that
they start to flag transactions as
suspicious if they get mixed regardless
if it's even a change change address
that's obviously that's not even trying
to be unknown anonymize but like you
know it's just a change address but if
it's coming out of the mix then they
just flag it as suspicious and consider
it as as the same as as all other other
coins those actually gain some anonymity
by mixing so it's it's interesting I
don't know when they will actually start
looking into it but it doesn't seem to
be the case for now well anyway let's
let's be ahead of them instead of behind
oh ok so oh my god we are really getting
out of this paper I just want to ask you
this so and you might be interested in
this question of mine too because you
know in wasabi we ship it with tour with
the tour Damon and we are communicating
with the back-end server through the
tour Damon of course our back-end is
running over onion anyway the thing is
that in Cohen joins many people come
together and then the round phases have
some timeouts and actually all the
Bitcoin privacy research projects have
demonstrated that oh we can do our
rounds in 12 seconds and things like
that and in practice at least in wasabi
or or or anywhere it's always the
slowest peer that that that blocks the
round and we started to log
how how how much someone is delayed and
it seems like our time outs has to be
around 12 around 1 minute 20 seconds or
or 2 minutes or yeah maybe 2 minutes so
the slowest peer that responds it takes
in two minutes so my question would be
what is there any faster
anonymity network that we could utilize
instead of Tor that is like consistently
fast for everyone and the slowest peer
doesn't block the whole around I mean a
little bit so are you saying that that
the Tor network you think is slowing
stuff down enough that that's causing
more than a minute delay it's very fast
usually so yeah 50 people in around or
let's say 190 people responds within 10
seconds so who cares but the remaining
10 is just very very slow and they are
broking they're round so the rounds
cannot progress as fast as we would hope
to and and and do you think those are
tor people being blocked by tour or just
that's like an hypothesis that's or
might be part of it the blocking no I
believe it's it's people from some
strange countries or or just the route
is going through some strange guy yeah
that might be the case so it's actually
there's this is great website about tour
called metrics tor project
org and that lets you sort of see the
the kind of average Layton sees and tor
in terms of you know at least retrieving
what different files and different
servers and it basically says you know
currently you're not really seeing
anything above more than a second a few
seconds
delay it looks like one second delay
round trip so my suspicion would be too
small the problem is that that's exactly
what you said that that if there's the
problem at or if you are you forcing
everyone to use tor in your network yes
ok so the issue there is that is exactly
what you said that someone because the
majority of tor entry/exit nodes are not
evenly geographically dispersed so if
I'm in a weird country all the time and
I don't know oh I'm just gonna make one
I'm just gonna guess let's say I'm in
Western Samoa the nearest tor entry node
maybe there might not even be an entry
node in Western Samoa it might have to
go all the way to Hawaii and then you
know balance to Japan and then bounce to
Europe and then bounce back to the US
and then to the mystic the the sabi mix
and it seems to me and this this has
been our practical experience mixed
networks in them is that the giant
slowdowns almost always come from from
certain geographical places running
running nodes which have just a huge
latency problem and that problem
actually nothing to do with tor it just
us do the asserted hop the Tor circuit
or more likely the end user themselves
is in a jurisdiction or location which
doesn't have great tour access so the
way we attack that problem in the nib
mix that is we say well you know if
you're not satisfying a certain kind of
quality of service we kick you out but
then you know that the Tor network is a
volunteer run Network so it's it's
harder to some extent to remove poor
performing relays real it toward note
relays that built to have circuits which
may not be working very well so I think
it's a trade-off Michelle we mean that
the thing with tor circuits is one way
you
maybe solve this problem I forget how
long it takes to build a new tourist
circuit but it's you know it's on the
order of a few seconds but if you're if
you're if you only need timing delays of
a minute if someone slow and also helps
in terms of privacy you should probably
force everyone to rebuild their tour
circuit at every round and so everyone's
going to slow down what appears to be
initial slowdown to rebuild their Tour
circuit but they would have better
privacy because then the tour circuits
between rounds would be much harder to
connect and then maybe you could do some
sort of test where you test people's
latency very quickly somehow I have to
think about how to do that you know just
send the bike backs in the bike Ford
before letting them do the coin joint so
you could detect people who are in these
as you put it these kind of strange
locations which have huge slow doubts or
happen to have tor circuits that go
through these strange locations it's a
good idea oh yeah by the way we are
changing tor streams extremely
frequently like if you have five outputs
to register then you are going to change
tor streams very quickly and what I
realized from my unit test that you can
ask tor to change its stream and it's
going to change 90% of the times but for
10% you just going best effort and just
put it put you to the exact same stream
where you were before but anyway it's
just yeah it's not trying to be a jerk I
think that's actually my understanding
because I've noticed that as well is
that tor is doing a lot of the trying to
avoid these slow circuits so they're
doing a lot of bandwidth balancing and
it happens to be in toward there's a few
tor nodes which have a lot of capacity
so you know if it's too expensive the
ability circuit or the
trying to optimize your there's a
certain frequent number of circuits
you're going to just keep using those
again and again because they work well
which is kind of backwards but I think
that's why I would bet that's why that's
happening mm-hmm anyway guys let's get
back to the paper how about that
and oh it's already an hour into this
conversation oh my god
time is flying yes so do you guys have
anything what what did you take away
from this paper or just just some
interesting things like like anonymity
is all one area of security that is much
younger for example than confidentiality
or or any quotes like this from the
paper
that's a long silence there so let's see
I just wanted to point out the thing
that Harry mentioned previously about
you know how tall works and all that I
just think that I'm not sure what's a
good way to quantify the anonymity of
Tor or even like precisely for Bitcoin
but I just think the main point would be
to have enough honest or not malicious
tor exit nodes and also for people to
like on and off ramps in Bitcoin also
without kyc I mean that's what I think
the biggest threat for this like the man
attack for just you know looking at that
Network I mean they can do the forcing
and all the other stuff like locally if
needed for true ISPs or to wallet
services service providers or something
like that if people ain't using their
own node but yeah I just think that's a
pretty interesting idea it concerns our
previous conversation and it might
settle something given the fundamental
differences in mechanisms they did they
employ the adversaries they are intended
to resist and their basic designs
not to mention typical applications it
might seem impossible or at least
astonishing that anyone who works in
this area would ever confuse the two yet
for years it has been common for
publications by even top researchers in
anonymity communication to refer to
point
routing networks as mix nets or vice
versa
even with designers of on your routing
systems have been exceptionally guilty
of failing into this idiom so yeah he
evens differentiate on your routing and
mixed nuts completely yeah I mean I
think the best quote that I found the
paper i which i think is this Paul
strongest point is he says well you know
you know mixed nut should be you so this
is on page at least 13 from the Free
Haven PDF mix that an entropy can be
used for applications where as possible
to manage and to measure sets of
distinct users and on enemy providers
and the probability distributions on
their behaviors with voting being a
clear example but for general internet
use
they are overkill against almost every
adversary except unrealistic ones which
is where me and Paul disagree like the
global passive adversaries or incredibly
strong ones like quote unquote demand
and because of usability incentive
limitations and practice they do not
scale them ups protect against the man
anyways on the other hand a widely
distributed network like tor may already
offer better although still inadequate
protection so that's yeah that's an
argument as argument is we really need
to worry it's and this is an argument
which i think bitcoin is actually ahead
was ahead of anonymous communication
research and and and also the the
general field of white consensus
algorithms because since algorithms are
always concerned about you know what
percentage of nodes have to be
compromised to destroy consensus or to
you know destroy the system in general
and that's typically you know people in
security and to some extent anonymous
communication research tend to think
kind of more an all-or-nothing and
actually it's kind of these local
attacks
where you say assume the enemy's
compromised some large section network
but not the whole network those are I
think realistic and and and you know
that the the cryptocurrency community
has a lot to teach the anonymous
communications community here it's and I
I don't know Paul's even looking at an
honest cryptocurrency but I think some
of the same insights about kind of
real-world anonymity versus on paper on
enemy is definitely applies to both
crypto in the Tor interesting thoughts I
I'm more on the side of rather the
critic community should be looking into
anonymous communications more because I
don't think we know enough yeah I mean
it does agree there I I'm a bit shocked
that there hasn't been more people
looking into it I remember a long time
ago I think there was some rumor that
chain alysus was running lots of the
kind of full knows seed nodes yes 10% is
that is that definitely true or I mean
it's a bit of rumor for a long time but
I had trouble figuring it out that was
definitely true
there was a whistleblower but he said it
was around 2014-15 but he also said that
now it's like they can't they don't run
run almost they don't run much yeah I
mean I would think that that's a pretty
big risk if they could run enough of
nodes but good to know the transaction
broadcasting stuff is pretty hard to
figure out yeah I mean not specifically
just that but for example if they have a
lot of notes they have a lot of
information about the network itself and
a lot of people use kyc I don't think it
mattered mattered that's not that much
if there are this like let's say 10 or
20% if
of people that are not using these kyc
exchanges and using mixing services I
mean they are pretty easy to narrow down
anyway I mean that the biggest threat is
if they get big mass to surveil I don't
know it's just my intuition so it was a
huge problem because blue filtering
wallets
we're the ones who but everyone was
pushing and and it turned out to be a
huge privacy risk if there is a huge
adversary who is trying to collect a
bunch of bloom filters now but what
might be the largest risk the
transaction broadcasting for that they
might try to identify where the
transactions coming from but what the
electrons are Airport right that that
[Music]
electrum servers know everything about
electrum users and electron users are
there are a lot so that's that could be
this could be the largest yeah yeah that
exactly has been one of my like things
that I've been worried about also the
amount of electron nodes just run from
by these blocking in block chain
analysis companies what what's better
centralized back-end servers or electrum
servers those are decentralized but you
know we said we had a windy boat but you
know we just it would be even better if
we could just somehow like I don't know
evolve into even a a better conclusion
or solution I mean just think about
something outside of box
oh yeah anyway thank you guys this was a
really interesting conversation and Oh
anyone would like to talk about anything
before before I I say goodbye I'm good
thanks
yeah this was thanks thanks for inviting
me I'll Ford out the loop picks paper
and the NIM link after the meeting and
yeah I think it should be good follow-up
to how the mix of that community
responded I think though all these
critiques which I think are at the time
their original these were very correct
from Paul and this why I'm not an
interface paper so this paper is
actually I think hugely important and I
I'm really glad you brought it up
because it it does really distinguish
between again you know why certain
real-world systems have really good
anonymity properties and how certain
systems we've seen that would be they
would be better might not but at the
same point what I want to try to say is
that you know that doesn't mean you
should just throw all the metrics now
that means you should try to make the
metrics more realistic and it improve
the system that you currently have so it
the because the thing about threat
models particularly things like the
global passive adversary this person
that's watching all the peer-to-peer
broadcasts or watching the Internet
traffic even you know even if you said
hey the NSA's watching our traffic even
you said that right before snowed in
2012 people would think you're a bit
crazy but then it ends up actually
harddrive space is cheap analysis is
quite good and you have something which
is very much more powerful than what
people thought that there were very few
attacks on cryptography but there was
because it was easy to do because hard
drive space is cheap we do know the NSA
was capable of doing mass metadata and
traffic analysis and I would assume that
the same case for cryptocurrency even
though we might not have as much
evidence and so we shouldn't even though
even the threat model seems unrealistic
we really should think what is likely
realistic given just what is actually
cheap it's gonna be very hard to break a
digital signature or to you know
anything like that but it might be easy
to just block a transaction or go after
seeding a node or you know go after a
central server and these are the things
that enemies are going to do so that's
wonderful
ending there and and hurry left
I think it's internet connection anyway
I'm stopping the recording thank you
guys
and woman have a good good day good
night thanks guys but thank you bye bye
guys thank you